'The men holding Bratton
used this boy as a suicide bomber.'
It's him. isn't it?
It looks like him.
He owes me a debt of honour.
'I demand the release of my brother.
Mohammed Jassim Ali.'
'Unless this holy warrior is freed.
the hostage will be executed.'
'Tell Porter he's been reactivated.'
"Porter's gone AWOL. sir." Have you
any idea where he might be headed?
"The tracker in his tooth
has him 35 clicks east of here."
"30 degrees. 30.24 minutes north.
47 degrees. 49 point..."
..at a safe house in an
apartment block in Basra City.
Go. go. go!
"It's a southern suburb of Basra -"
Yes!
I know it. Porter's chasing
the only lead he has.
He's outside the safe house that
was used to hold Kenneth Bratton.
Do you want me to contact Basra
police. have them intercept Porter?
No.
He's waited seven years for
a second chance. Let him have it.
'Shoot him! John. shoot him!'
It's OK.
Hakim Al Nazeri.
Hakim Al Nazeri!
We're both gonna have a much easier
time if you can speak English.
I speak English.
Good.
Where is Hakim Al Nazeri?
I don't know what you're talk...
Aaaargh! Aieee!
Alright. Let's try that again.
shall we?
Point one. our friends there came
running after hearing his name.
Point two. before the invasion this
place was a safe house for a hostage.
I know that.
I was sent to get him out.
Point three. I'm gonna start using
this knife in more inventive ways
unless you tell me where
they're holding
the remaining 95 percent
of the English infidel.
They will kill you. my friend.
Maybe.
Or maybe they'll hear what I've got
to trade.
You need to ask yourself how much
Hakim wants Jassim out of Belmarsh.
Who is this?
Do you miss me?
"Porter!"
I contacted Sword of Islam.
I'm off to rendezvous
with my pet theory. Hakim?
Could be a trap.
could be a wild goose chase.
I'm gonna have to hang up now.
Porter. keep this line open.
Porter?! Shit!
So. now we can't be traced. OK?
Take the next left.
What are you doing?
Call of nature.
This road better be flat.
Is this it?
You'll soon find out.
Out!
Aaargh! It hurts!
We really can't go on like this.
All yours. hero.
Who are you? I'm sorry. sir.
I can't answer that question.
We've just lost Porter.
We've lost him. too. Shit!
We lost contact with Bravo team
at 15:21 GMT. 18:21 local time.
In our last communication he claimed
to be heading to a rendezvous
with a former Mukhabarat colonel.
Hakim Al Nazeri.
a man we believe might be the
commander of Sword of Islam.
This satellite image of Al Kanan
was Porter's last known position.
It was taken at 18:36 local time
and shows four vehicles outside the
building. Track the vehicles?
No. By the time we got a second
satellite image an hour ago.
the vehicles were gone. And Porter.
We have Charlie team on standby.
We can have then on the ground
in Basra in five hours.
And a helicopter to where they might
find clues to Katie's whereabouts.
Or a booby-trap.
We have less than 52 hours
before they execute Katie.
If we delay - Hugh. count yourself
lucky the Sword of Islam
haven't already posted pictures of
dead soldiers on their website.
Authorisation denied.
We've lost five men in 25 hours.
What did you expect? Sir. Porter has
given us this location.
We can't let these men's deaths be
in vain. I've no intention of that.
You find me another mission as
cover... and you've got Charlie team.
Sir.
Hi. Alexandra.
Is your mother here?
Mum!
This is about my dad. isn't it?
Hugh.
Diane.
GCHQ monitoring recorded John
has a lost signal.
Please speak English.
Alex.
Your father volunteered for a
dangerous mission in Iraq.
Who sent him?
You know I can't tell you that.
You. You sent him. didn't you?
I can't go into detail but the
manner in which we lost contact
with John makes us feel that -
Don't you dare! Don't you dare!
My dad's not..
I'm so sorry.
No. get off me!
You're a liar!
Alex...
Listen. um...
..I know how much you've done
for John. Thank you.
But... the truth is. Er...
..we're all better off without him.
Diane. he was -
No. you're better off too.
Whatever it was that made you
look out for him...
..it's gone. You're free.
Who are you?
Katie...
My name's John.
I'm SAS.
It's alright. don't be frightened.
Katie...
..we're gonna get you out of here.
OK?
You're a brave girl.
Brave girl.
Shh. It's OK.
It's OK.
Shh.
Katie. look at me. Look at me.
Whatever happens. trust me!
You trust me!
You said you were here to negotiate.
Is that true? Sorry. sir.
I can't answer that question.
What is your mission? I'm sorry.
sir. I can't answer that question.
By what means do the British plan
to rescue the hostage?
I'm sorry. sir.
I can't answer that question.
No! No! No. no!
What are you doing?! No!
Tell me.
Let me talk to her! If she wants me
to talk. she can tell me.
Katie. Katie. look at me.
Look at me.
Trust me.
Just so you know. I'm gonna kill
every single of of these bastards.
Tell me! I'm sorry. sir.
I can't answer that question.
Tell me!
I'm sorry. sir. I can't answer
that question.
Leave her alone. you fucker!
Leave her alone!
You let her suffer... to resist me.
You're not gonna kill her. Not while
you still have her to bargain with.
Katie Dartmouth's death was
inevitable the moment I took her.
But because of you. I'm forced to
bring forward the deadline
for her execution.
We will kill her tomorrow at dawn.
And you will be first.
"Charlie Team have been
deployed undercover
of a joint operation
with our American friends."
"How quickly can you be
where we lost Porter's signal?"
We can be airborne immediately.
Good work.
Shh. It's OK. It's OK.
It's only me. It's John.
We're gonna get through this.
You and me.
You know that. don't you?
Yes.
Good girl.
I'm just gonna loosen these ropes
to make you more comfortable.
Is that better?
Yeah.
How does that arm feel?
Just numb.
I need to have a look at it.
Is that OK?
Yeah. OK.
Clear!
'Clear!'
How did you find me? The photo
you took of the young man...
..led me to you.
Really. I just wanted an autograph.
Looks good.
There's no infection.
Now listen.
They'll come for me first.
That's our chance. I'll overpower
them. Then I'll come back for you.
Gonna get you home. Katie.
I'll need to put this hood back on.
I'm sorry.
I understand.
OK.
Oh. please don't go.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm right here. I'm right here.
OK. OK.
'I think Porter
might still be alive.'
'They've cleaned out. left the body
of one of their soldiers.'
My guess is he's the man
who led Porter to them.
If they left his body. Porter's
would be there. It stands to reason.
There's a chance he's alive. We can
effect a rescue. Sir. One moment.
All Islam locations are within
30 kilometres of each other.
If we centre a radius
from the point of abduction.
we narrow the search to specific
sites. Know the car he was driving?
Yeah. a Range Rover. "Get back
to base but be airborne by dawn."
We'll give you new coordinates
for an aerial search.
You've got 25 hours. Layla.
There's still time.
"This is Alpha.
Resuming search. Over."
Don't move.
What? What are we...?
Where are you taking me? John!
John. where are they taking me?
Oh. God! No!
Don't be frightened! Trust me.
Help me! You bastard!
You said you'd take me first!
I lied.
Just coming up now. sir.
Our demand for the release
of our brother has gone unheeded.
They have shown no intention
of negotiating in good faith.
That is why we shall execute Katie
Dartmouth in a few short minutes.
Layla. they've brought it forward.
They'll execute Katie this morning.
No! No!
No! Don't!
No! No! No!
No! No!
Oh. God! No!
Katie!
Don't shoot him. Don't. You know
why I have to kill you. don't you?
Please!
I wanna hear you say it!
John. think.
He could have shot you.
This is for killing
Mike and Keith and for Steve.
He says it wasn't him.
No shit. He's got a gun in his face!
Does he look like a killer?
He swears he didn't kill your
friends. Who did? Tell me that.
We have to go now.
Move!
Go! Move! Move!
Go.
"Heading north."
"Continuing towards the radius."
"Any developments?" They haven't
uploaded the execution.
Until we hear otherwise.
assume Katie and Porter are alive.
Hold on!
John.
Yep.
Give me a shout
if you see a phone box. Telephone?
John.
Fuck.
Come on. pick up.
"This is Lieutenant Thompson. Please
leave a message." Shit. Redial. OK.
Hold on!
We need to get off this road.
Hello?
Hello? John!
Layla? Layla. it's Porter.
Porter. thank God! Sir.
we have contact from Bravo Team.
Hold on. Layla.
Right. get out.
get down behind the wheels.
We have to make a stand. I have the
hostage. We now have the hostage.
Bravo has Dartmouth. sir.
She's alive.
What's your position?
Repeat. what's your position. Bravo?
Just turned off a desert highway
heading southwest
at an intersection of high voltage
pylons running north-south.
Two vehicles in pursuit.
"Found you. On our way. ETA
four minutes. Repeat. four minutes."
Fuck.
Pass me that. I also have Scarface.
Repeat. I also... Layla?
"Porter?"
Layla!
"Porter. can you hear me?"
Shit.
"We have a visual on the pylons."
"15km from target.
ETA three minutes."
Fuck.
Shit.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
No! Hold position!
There's someone else with Bravo.
sir!
It's Scarface. sir!
"I'll put you on head-cam."
"Confirm. Bravo has the SOI soldier.
designation Scarface!"
"Do we extract new contact?"
"Do you copy?"
"Do we extract new contact
with Bravo and hostage?"
Extraction denied.
Repeat. do not extract Scarface.
Copy.
"Landing now."
Stay low.
Head down!
Not you! On your knees!
Katie. sit here.
"This is 28 Alpha.
Hostage secure. Moving now."
What? What are you doing?
Wait! As'ad!
John. they're leaving him!
Layla. we need to go back now!
Orders from Collinson!
They'll kill him!
No! Collinson. we need to go back!
Now!
"Collinson. just give the order!"
"Zero. this is 28 Alpha.
Do we return?"
"Repeat. do we return? Over."
"Collinson. don't do this!"
"Collinson. you bastard! Collinson!
Collinson!"
"The abducted television journalist
Katie Dartmouth
is recovering in a US air base after
a daring rescue..."
"Although no details have been
released by the Ministry of Defence.
sources have told us that
the rescue came moments before
the deadline was announced
for her execution."
"Miss Dartmouth is expected
to fly home tomorrow morning."
"We have this report..."
Oh. my God!
Dad! Dad!
Yeah?
John.
That's very kind.
I'm one of the lucky ones.
I came home.
My father supported the invasion
and the war that followed.
an extension of which
is still going on in Afghanistan.
My family have had a taste
of what British forces
and Iraqi families have gone through
these past few years.
And we are humbled by it.
My heart goes out to those families
on both sides
whose loved ones
will never come home.
I owe you an apology.
Oh?
You did an extraordinary thing
out there.
Not gonna kiss me. are you?
No.
Don't get all sentimental on me
like that.
I think I preferred you
with low self-esteem.
What will you do now?
I'm gonna see a man about a job.
I'm glad you came in.
As a friend. I owe you
an explanation about Scarface.
As'ad.
Yes.
I was forced to weigh
the intelligence value
he might have been able to provide
against the risk he posed
as a known terrorist.
Suppose he'd had a change of heart
and tried to bring down
the helicopter?
We could've lost Katie on the very
brink of getting her to safety.
Katie.... I need you to tell me
everything As'ad said to you.
About what happened
the night you saved his life? Yeah.
He said...
He said that the man who killed
your friends was another soldier.
An Iraqi soldier...
..or a British soldier?
You do understand. don't you. John?
Of course.
I would've done exactly the same
thing if I was in your shoes.
Good.
So. have you come to a decision?
About our offer to join Section 20?
Yeah.
Yes. I have.